HELCIO ANDRÉ

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

helcioandre@live.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList | Medium | Portfolio

SUMMARY

I am a web developer that loves to create beautiful, effective products with enjoyable user experiences. Pair-programming and remote work aficionado. Fluent in multiple languages, frameworks, and technologies, and capable of self-learning quickly and efficiently.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, ¡Query, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS
Full Stack Web Developer

Remote

September 2020 - Present

Finished technical curriculum including a wide variety of front-end and back-end projects, held daily meetings with the standup team to report progress, worked with several coding partners in an international pair programming environment.

Todo-list-app — A todo app where the user can Add/Edit/Delete todos. GitHub | Live

Built with: JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, Webpack

Weather-app — An app that gets user location and fetches the current weather from the open weather API. The user can search from more than 220 cities around the world. <u>GitHub | Live</u>

• Built with: JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, Webpack, JSON, open weather API

Covid-19-scraper — This app scrapes for data at https://www.worldometers.info/coronavirus, presents general information in tables and allows the user to search statistics about covid-19 by country.

<u>GitHub</u>

• Built with: Ruby, Ruby gems

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

October 2020 – April 2021

- Helped students adapt quickly to the fast-paced learning environment at Microverse.
- Clarify doubts and point mentees in the right directions to improve their knowledge and skills.
- Provided mental and motivational support when needed.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

September 2020 - present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers. simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.